Okay, so we're going to dive into
installation of the OpenShift Container Platform.
As I mentioned, we're going to start with
a with a user provisioned infrastructure.
Then we'll go through
an installer provisioned infrastructure from
ACM and then in later demonstrations we'l get into the manage services.
Before we dive in, I do want to point out we do
have full stack automation using IPI and the left,
which is kind of an
opinionated best practices
for cluster provisioning.
Although majority of our
installation is actually
still follow a preexisting
infrastructure.
You know, when you get
into a data center
and there's a lot of existing,
very heterogeneous
infrastructure, hardware,
networking and those sorts of
things that need
to be supported.
And so we need to meet customers
where they are today in
their infrastructure
and be able to
support that with user
provision infrastructure.
And then you could see all
those offerings on the right.
So with that, let
me stop sharing
that screen and go over
to the installation.
So we're going to start
where most of our sysadmins,
an OpenShift admins
will be familiar with,
and that is at the command line.
So I have a environment here,
a Linux shell that I'm at.
I want to show you
what it looks like
to actually deploy via
API, user provision
infrastructure.
You're gonna notice
a few things.
I have them install config
dot YAML file here.
This is really the majority
of what the inflation
gets powered off of.
So this install config YAML
file had some details in it.
This is probably the
most challenging part.
Setup is this install config
YAML file and get it correct.
Because you need to talk to
various teams like
you're this case,
since we're deploying on
B sphere, you're obese,
your administrators,
your networking team,
your DNS team, and so on to
understand and coordinate
with them what
you can use inside
those environments to
deploy your OpenShift cluster.
So once I have that installed
config, it's pretty
straightforward.
I could basically, there's
a couple of commands.
One is I'm just going
to run the OpenShift,
install, create
ignition configs.
And what that will do screen.
It will have created
some ignition biology.
See a master admission file at
Bootstrap and worker
admission file.
These ignition files are
going to get appended to
the config of the
virtual machines
on vSphere so that when
they're powered on,
they take over and actually
feed the information
necessary to
those machines to be
installed properly,
to be part of this cluster.
So from there, I've
actually written a couple
of scripts to make
this a little easier
rather than clicking around,
I have a set VM
config dot SH script.
All that script does is
use a small client
called me go VC,
which is a very popular
Go binary based.
These your client,
basically it interacts
the vSphere API to manipulate
your vSphere environment.
So I go here and
run, set the config.
That's going to do
is it's gonna go,
you'll see it's actually
printing out what you have here.
So it's basically taking
that ignition file
and adding it to
each VM so that the VM is set
up for to boot from
that ignition file.
Then I'm gonna run the
power on shell command.
Again, just using Vigo B2C
client reach out to beads here,
Empower on the machines. So
we'll go ahead and do that.
The nice thing is,
once this is done,
once I've set this VM config
and power them on from there.
All I do is really just wait.
So I'm going to go ahead
and run this
OpenShift installed.
Wait for Bootstrap to complete,
and this'll just wait until
that API is available.
It takes roughly 20 minutes
for this to complete.
So in this other window here,
you can see what this
output will look
like once the
installation is complete.
So you can see here,
if I go to open this up,
I open this URL.
It's going to take me
right into the cluster.
And you can see,
you can see if I go to the
administrator persona,
this cluster is now running,
was deployed by a user
provision infrastructure.
Now to make this a hub cluster,
as we were showing in our demo,
we want to make
this hub cluster so
we can deploy subsequent.
We can deploy subsequent
clusters using
ACM by IPI makes it much easier.
I can just go to Operator hub,
click on Advanced cluster
management kubernetes
and install this operator.
So I'm gonna go ahead
and install this.
And this will take about two
to three minutes install.
Once it's installed,
then it'll become
a hub cluster that can be
used to deploy
additional clusters.
For the sake of the demo,
let me go ahead and
just go into ACM. Here.
We'll get back and oh, sorry,
it's actually over here.
Let me go back to
ACM. If I go to ACM,
you'll notice that when you come
in you get the dashboard view.
So this is advanced
cluster management.
I'm going to go to
the clusters menu
on the left-hand side here.
And I can actually create
a new cluster a
straight from here.
So once I have UPI
deployed by UPI,
made that a hub cluster,
I go into Advanced
cluster management.
I can begin creating
clusters straight from here.
So I'll go ahead and
hit Create cluster.
In this case, I'm going
to use VMware vSphere.
Let's go ahead and select
the vSphere
infrastructure provider.
We'll call this Boston.
I wanted to, I could add
this to a cluster set.
I'm going to clusters
that's basically just a
grouping for management
purposes and ACM,
I'm going to select
the latest release.
I'm not going to do single
node OpenShift today.
Under node pools, I can,
I can customize the sizes
and the accounts of my
control of my worker.
Nodes as well as
their memory and CPU core
sockets, all that stuff.
I'm going to leave those
as is for the networks.
Again, you do need to
understand what these
are going to be.
So in this case, we're going to
need a public network
on the sphere.
So I'll go ahead and
add that in there.
You need the API that,
that's the virtual IP address
that the culture will
communicate over.
And that's the Ingrid's virtual
IP address for traffic.
I'm not going to use a proxy.
If I wanted to, I could extend
this installation with
ansible templates.
So if there's
something outside of
the installer, outside of IPI,
the installer provision
infrastructure
flow that I want to do,
update a CMDB, send
an e-mail integrated service,
now something of that sort.
I could use Ansible to do that.
And then I can simply review
this and then hit Create.
Before I hit Create,
I just want to point
out all of this is
actually see this all
in YAML as well, read
on the right hand side.
So if you wanted
to kinda copy and
paste and reproduce
these configurations,
you could do so
relatively easily,
so that I'll hit Create.
And this should kick off and
begin deploying our cluster.
So you've got the view here.
But hopefully that gives you
a good idea of how you can
deploy clusters
using UPI, an API.
Now I'm going to hand
it over to Chuck,
who's going to walk you
through the deployment of
an actual Red Hat
OpenShift service
on Amazon Web Services.