All right, Thank you, James.
Okay, Let's pivot a bit to talk about
Cloud services through the lens of sales.
The level set.
Again, let's talk about what we mean
when we say Red Hat Cloud services.
Red Hat Cloud services is divided
into three different segments,
platform, application and data services.
Platform services are OpenShift Dedicated,
Rosa, ARO and OSE,
also known as managed OpenShift.
Application services,
are our API Management Kafka
and service strategy projects
with her via higher or dev level layers
of abstraction for,
for our customers to build
new applications and modernize existing.
And finally data services,
roads and Rohde wishes are data science
and data access broker products, respectively.
We're going to talk mostly
about Rosa here
in a few moments,
but just again to level set,
this is the full
breadth and depth of
our Cloud services portfolio,
which is really helps
her support our
customers and their,
and their journeys
to be cloud native.
All right, so why does read as
sales love run at
Cloud services?
Well, the nice thing
about our Cloud services,
especially ARO and Rosa,
and allows us to so with
the Cloud providers
rather than a guest,
the Cloud providers, and that
removes a ton of our friction.
Ton of friction between our
companies allows us to tap
into the enormous sales
and delivery teams.
These Cloud providers
have an unlocks a heck
of a lot more addressable
market and we can
get on our own.
Arvin said in the
previous session,
that we are not at war
with hyperscalers,
but they are in fact a friend.
This is exactly what we mean.
This has made all possible
because really the Cloud
services providers
have trained our customers
where they are today and
train them around technical.
Basically, you know, how easy is
it to get access and
turn on resiliency,
availability scale,
they all LEDs, right?
And financial in terms
of a way to buy just what
they need at the time.
Just in time it's single
bill makes it super,
super easy for procurement.
So let's pivot to talk
about AWS, right?
Specifically selling with them
rather than against them.
And this is simply
because if you
look at our all of our
deployments for OpenShift,
for that matter, AWS makes
up about 20 percent of them.
So they are by far
the number one hyperscaler which
OpenShift is in
fact deploy, right?
And so let's talk about Rosa,
which is Red Hat
OpenShift service on AWS.
This is our native first-party
service that exist on
AWS that customers can buy
and transact through Amazon,
through the console, right?
So Rosa is specifically
a Cloud native experience
that they get.
So they get that
OpenShift experience that
developers and operators
love in Amazon.
As easy as they've
ever had before.
All right?
And this is important, my seat
experience because one of
the greatest value
propositions of
OpenShift is that there's
a consistent experience,
really no matter where you
run, especially for workloads.
So it really helps bolster from
a technical perspective
the, the hybrid story,
while we are abstracting
away the underlying
complexity of
the Cloud providers and
even hybrid on-prem
infrastructure.
Right?
Back in a past life,
I lead a bunch of
development teams and one of
the most expensive
things that a deal with,
having different teams really
focusing on different
environments or stacks.
And so they really weren't
fungible with each other.
Something like
OpenShift specifically,
Rosa technically
allows me to have
a consistent
experience no matter
where where where were right.
Right. And then also
specific to Rosa,
which is much different than the
typical self-manage OpenShift
experience, is that,
you know, we're
meeting customers and
what they expect from technical
experience of having,
you know, a cluster up with
a few clicks as possible.
And we've made huge
improvements on this.
And Rosa, and we're
making even more so
in the future, right?
So we put at their fingertips.
So the, the burden of adoption,
of barriers and adoption
are much lower.
On the financial side of it,
It's really important not
the all Rosa consumption
retires the Cloud provider
or the commitments made to
the Cloud providers, right?
In Amazon's with respect
to w ADP, right?
That means, is it that our
customers have triggered there
are some sign these very
large commitments that said,
I'm going to spend this much
money on your platform.
You're going to get
any bit of a break,
you're gonna give me,
let's say, I promise
has been so, so much.
You're going to give me
a dollar 20th services
for every dollar I spend, right?
And then from a
procurement perspective,
even beyond that, that,
that commitment retirement,
which we'll see here
in a second too,
is that you get
everything on one bill.
So you see your rows
usage right next
to all the underlying EC2
network and storage, right?
And this experience,
as we've already seen,
major, major leap forward
in terms of how
customers are using it.
For example, we'll
call one customer
financial services customer that
got into rows a self-service
because of the technical
self-service aspect of it.
Has the financial aspect of it.
They weren't even a
customer Red Hat.
They got into it this summer.
And now with a little help from
our Black Belt customer
success teams.
They're the number one
consumer of Rosa on
a ARR basis, which is huge.
All right, so let's check
this out a little bit, right?
I want to walk through what
Rosa self-service
install looks like.
So we're going to go to good,
use the AWS CLI
and the Rosa CLI,
which is the four.
Whereas AWS CLI is what
most Amazon users and
administrators use to
STI and HIV services,
configure their
environment, etc.
All right, and then
what we're gonna do
is we're going to compare
that to what looks
like to stand up EKS.
Not to say that Rosa an EKS
are even really comparison
because one's an
application platform,
the other one is
Kubernetes infrastructure.
But as I mentioned earlier,
like the behaviors that are that
these cloud providers are
trained or customers on.
I want to show you how similar
these experiences are.
So for me, we talk to customers.
Really, they're not going to
have to learn a whole lot
of new stuff or are
really not a whole lot
of new processes to
get there because to
get the clusters up.
Alright, so let's pull
up my command line here.
And the first thing I'm
gonna do is I'm going to log
into amazon USE Stu.
And this is a little
cooking show thing because
I've already inputted
my credentials,
so that's just there.
Now I'm gonna do is
Rosa create cluster.
Let me name this puppy.
Demo.
One. Right.
Now we're off to
the races, right?
So this will take
about 30 minutes
and by the time this is done,
I'll have a full
OpenShift cluster.
Ready, got Rosa cluster
ready to go on Amazon.
All right, so let's see what
the experience was like for
another service on Amazon,
specifically EKS, right?
So AWS Configure,
configure log in.
All right, Well again,
and now I'm going to
use what they have,
the AKS command
line, EKS CTL spray.
So just one other CLI,
EKS, CTL Create cluster.
And there is a very small change
in terms of the parameters.
And that is name and name is,
we'll just say CSF will be
KS one or something, right?
And there we go.
Alright?
Now often racism will have
an AKS cluster of
about 20 minutes.
All right, so one thing
I'm sure you all notice.
One thing we've got dinged
on a lot in the past is,
you know, how long it takes
to get a cluster up, right?
Well, I can tell you from
a rose at ETS perspective.
First of all, that was
super easy to do right?
In.
And secondly, that 30
minutes is because not
only are you put in,
you know, Kubernetes,
he's out there or
a smattering on
all the other really
awesome value
out of distractions
that makes OpenShift,
OpenShift on top of
the cluster, right?
So that's, that's
very different.
So basically in the,
in the time it takes to
watch Seinfeld episode,
you can have Rosa
cluster up and you know,
our our customers or our
off to the races using it.
One thing usually, in my
earlier years here at Red Hat,
specifically with OpenShift V3,
I would always say preface,
any demo, do that.
Customer with, boy, I hope I
sacrificed and
solutions architects
to the demo gods last night.
So I can have a good demo.
I can tell you today and now
we're turning on clusters is so easy with Rosa, an ARO.
No sacrifices needed.
I know it's going
to work every time,
which is totally
awesome and that is
the experience that
our customers are
expecting in the Cloud.
All right, So we went over
the technical portion, right?
The second Weber's.
Now let's look at
the financial part.
So what I want to show you
here is my Amazon bill.
It shows Rosa and all my
EC2 and it's right here.
So as you can see in February,
I've spent about $2281
on Amazon services,
which includes Rosa my
apologies, the Julia accident.
You'll be getting this
expense report very soon.
We also have another really
cool view here, right?
So this is console
dot write this as
our Hybrid Cloud Console
for, for OpenShift.
That shows me all my connected
OpenShift clusters, right?
Ccds here, there's
some over here
it has CP, things like that.
Think of it as almost
like an ACM light.
What is in here is there's
a cost management feature
where I can actually connect
my console dot experience up
to the billing providers
of the different Cloud
providers, right?
So as you see here,
you have opened
that are Amazon Web Services,
Azure, GCP, et cetera.
So I am AWS connected up here.
I'm going to click this. And
now you see this account.
And what you see is
this historical data
in terms of my usage, right?
As you can see,
there's a little bit of
break here because I turn
my clusters off so it wasn't
being charged anything, right?
But this is a, this is
super important and
very cold for our
customers understand.
Because again, this removes
so much of the procurement and
the financial friction away
from a buying OpenShift
that they would
typically have for,
for self-managed,
right? All right.
So let's go back to the deck.
Okay, So I also
remember I talked about
consistency, right?
So consistency is key,
consistent openness
to experience.
No matter where
you choose arrive.
To show this, I'm going to go on
to advanced cluster
manager, ACM.
And I'm going to
launch an application,
same application across
a vSphere cluster,
ana Rosa cluster, right?
That's important in this view.
The sphere in
Amazon Web Services
are wildly different
infrastructure.
But again, that value add,
that value proposition of,
of OpenShift is that
consistent experience
that really abstracts
away that complexity.
You heard me talk
before, you heard me say
this and enzymes, but
I'll say it again.
The value proposition of
OpenShift is that we unlock
the power of containers and
cube well hiding their,
hiding their complexity, which
includes airline emperor.
So hurry up.
I will add a label.
It's called Book of a
very simple, right?
And there is an application
catalog that, that's
associated with.
So that's a V sqrt cluster.
And I'll just add one to
one of my Rosa clusters.
I stood up previously that
touched again cooking
shows to help.
All right. Now if I look at
the application catalog here,
I will go find that
book info application.
And here you see
the architecture or the topology
or other of that application.
Just to prove to
you that this was
not some sort of
slide where vapor,
I will now show you that,
hey, I'm actually running.
So this is that
application running on
vSphere and use
that exact same application
running on Rosa.
Totally awesome,
consistent experience.
If I had multiple teams
out there working on this,
one wouldn't have to be
trained and vSphere,
another one won't
have to be trained
and an amine Amazon, again,
Oba shift just kind of a
lock step for them and
locks the power of technology
is like container and cube.
To get your applications
out there as quickly
as possible,
I get while hiding the
underlying complexity.
All right, next slide.
Okay.
So one of the things
that I'll close with
is something that is super
important for
customers understand.
And that is the Red Hat Site
Reliability Engineering
or SRE team.
These are experts that manage
our managed OpenShift clusters
are Cloud services
for that matter,
all of them behind
the scenes, right?
In, Let's be honest
with ourselves here,
there's no one better out
there to, to operate.
Red Hat Cloud
services are read at
Red Hat Software than red
adders themselves, right?
Is a set of product engineers,
systems engineers, the
intersection of that right?
They began to become basically
a virtual team member
of your customers
operations and SRE teams.
This is super
important in terms of
lowering the total
cost of ownership.
So that the customers can then
focus the resources on
what really matters.
And that's delivering
applications.
This is the say that
with our SRE team,
we're enabling our customers
the resiliency of the platform.
We continuous uptime
to move from 24,
7 operations to 95 innovations.
And that 95 innovations,
which is helping customers
deliver applications to prod,
breaking the land
speed record, right?
That is what drives
consumption from
a selling perspective that
is hypercritical or Red Hat.
And this is again,
another reason
why we love Cloud services.
All right.
I think it's back to James
to her application
modernization.
Thank you.